Toronto, ON - Canada hoffande@gmail.com | +1 (437) 388-2440

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER | RESEARCH ASSISTANT

I am a researcher in the field of chaos theory, time series and data analysis, with a solid background in Physics, Mathematics and Statistics. Moreover, I have an extensive laboratory and data analysis practise, carry good managerial skills and teaching abilities. I am highly motivated to fulfil a position in research and/or data-analysis, focusing on generation of insights and knowledge to help the company to deliver excellence services, and to impact people's life.

EXPERIENCE

SANTA CATARINA STATE UNIVERSITY | Postdoctoral Researcher

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019 | Joinvile, SC - Brazil

- Postdoctoral researcher at the Physics Department, focusing on electronic chaotic circuits, with experimental, theoretical and computational resources.
- Time series collection, analysis and characterization through Chaos Theory fundamentals.
- Development of new tools and routines for computational analysis of large datasets using R.
- Co-supervised Master and Graduating students.
- Collaborated with researchers to advance research and gain deeper understanding of chaotic systems behavior, with three publications in high-impact scientific journals.

SOCIESC UNIVERSITY | PROFESSOR (PART-TIME)

Mar 2018 - Aug 2018 | Jaragua do Sul, SC - Brazil

- Physics Professor in Engineering classes.
- Created new lessons plans based on course objectives.

CATOLICA DE SANTA CATARINA UNIVERSITY | PROFESSOR (PART-TIME)

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018 | Jaragua do Sul, SC - Brazil

• Provided on-line support for students in Math, Calculus I and II, Algebra, Physics I and II.

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF PARANA | RESEARCH ASSISTANT (PHD CANDIDATE)

Mar 2014 - Dez 2017 | Curitiba, PR - Brazil

- Researched on development and characterization of thin-film solar cells.
- Helped with large survey research projects and provided research support for data processing operations.
- Planned, modified, and executed research techniques, procedures and tests.
- Prepared materials for reports, presentations and submission to peer-reviewed journal publications.
- Cleaned and maintained equipment in good working conditions.
- Four publications in high-impact scientific journals.

SKILLS

GENERAL

Problem Solving • Logical Thinking • Research and analysis • Portuguese/English

PROGRAMMING

R • MS Office • Tableau • Fortran • LATEX • GnuPlot

CHAOS THEORY

Chaotic system dynamics • Time series analysis

LABORATORY

Electronic Circuits • Lab procedures • Solar cells • Organic devices • Impedance Spectroscopy

EDUCATION

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF PARANA | PHD IN PHYSICS

Dec 2017 | Curitiba, PR - Brazil

SANTA CATARINA STATE UNIVERSITY | MASTER IN PHYSICS

Feb 2014 | Joinville, SC - Brazil

SANTA CATARINA STATE UNIVERSITY | BACHELOR IN PHYSICS

Mar 2007 | Joinville, SC - Brazil

COMPETENCIES

- Goal-oriented and excel to complete ongoing projects with outstanding results.
- Display strong analytical qualities and achieve results with accuracy and precision.
- Able to adapt to new concepts, master new skills quickly and implement new knowledge.
- Conscious about deadlines and able to handle stressful circumstances.
- Troubleshoot problems systematically and purpose applicable solutions.
- Teach and communicate to diverse audiences, including both specialist and non-specialist.

LINKS

LinkedIn: anderson-hoff • Google Scholar: Anderson Hoff • Github: AndersonHoff

ACTIVE RESEARCH

Passionate about data analysis and data science, I am developing routines in R to make analysis and forecast of data from different sources. Main research topics include:

- Data analysis and visualization with Tableau.
- Time Series analysis and prediction.
- Analysis of chaotic patterns in experimental and numerical data.
- Machine Learning

PUBLICATIONS

9 scientific papers published in international peer-reviewed journals, as Solar Energy Materials and Solar Cells, Physics Letters A, European Physical Journal of Materials Science, International Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos. The complete list can be accessed in:

- Publons:// Anderson Hoff
- Google Scholar:// Anderson Hoff

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Physics Professor • Calculus and Algebra Professor • Car repair specialist • Half-marathon runner